# SACHIN AHUJA

sachinahj@gmail.com | sachinahuja.info | Santa Monica, CA

# FULL-STACK/DATA ENGINEERING

Software engineering expert with 5 years of committed client service in business intelligence and data analytic applications. Specialize in software development and data engineering functions. Spearhead and drive a multitude of high-profile research and data analytics projects. Driven to find technical and data-centered solutions for companies' greatest challenges in an effort to add value. Serve as a leader in the mentoring and coaching of other team members by teaching them techniques, processes and applications used in data management.

#### **CORE PROFICIENCIES**

Data Engineering | Product Management | Project Implementation | Project Management Web & Application Development | Troubleshooting | Process Improvement | End-User and Customer Support

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

# **ATOM TICKETS**

#### **Software Design Engineer**

2017 - Present

- Engineer a revolutionary, user-friendly, and socially-driven interface that allows movie lovers to search for films
  instantly, invite friends, buy tickets, pre-order concessions and enjoy a VIP experience at the theater
- Assist with the application planning, development, and deployment of Atom's and Regal's web clients using Scala, Play Framework, and JavaScript
- Integrate Google Pay and Chase Pay into the checkout flow for higher user conversion
- Sought and implemented special partnership promotions to help increase traffic with Amazon Prime and Lionsgate/AMEX exclusive screenings, decreasing CPA by 26%
- Implement advertisement placements with Adzerk support to manage scheduling and goal tracking
- Led in the development of ADA compliance for Regal Cinemas

# <u>Visa</u>

# **Senior UI Engineer**

2016 - 2017

- Charged with enhancing the UI implementation in a forward-thinking, reusable, and scalable UI architecture
- Designed React web components taken from prototypes, partnering exclusively with design, engineering, and product teams to ensure project alignment
- Developed the following web components:
  - Advanced Search, Advanced Dropdown, Date-Time Picker, Status, Status Manager
- Partnered with the team to author documentation for the reusable web components open-sourced within the company
- Increased the coverage of the UI unit testing framework using Enzyme

#### **DRAFTCRUNCH**

#### **Lead Software Developer** (engg team of two)

2015 - 2016

- Partnered with the co-founders to build a venture-backed sports analytics platform for daily fantasy sports players to create, sell, and/or purchase third-party predictive models and strategies acquiring 15,000 users
- Engineered a web service, with cached architecture, master-slave cluster, and sticky sessions for web-sockets to create the fastest responsive lineup builder in the industry

- Developed the lineup builder web client using Angular.js, which serves as a complex analytical tool to analyze and create lineups
- Directed flow of assignments by delegating smaller sub-tasks to team members and contractors monitoring project progress along the way
- Created ETL services integrated with 3rd party APIs and web scrapers to get the latest information for the platform
- Crafted an image rendering microservice for social sharing of lineups to create virality
- Rectified immediately any production bottlenecks, performed unit testing, and test drove development, ensuring maximum quality assurance during every phase of development

#### **TOGGA**

### Web Developer (engg team of three)

2014 - 2015

- Produced the first-ever Women's World Cup fantasy app acquiring 110,000 users, using Ionic.js and Node.js microservices deployed on Docker
- Contributed to building high-performance cloud-based REST API services, handling 30,000 daily active users using Node.js, PHP, MySQL and Redis
- Enhanced the Draft app from end to end by configuring a microservice to handle scheduled events and incorporating real-time data support using Firebase
- Spearheaded the migration of the web client architecture from jQuery to Angular.js
- Programmed an email campaign manager to augment retention by sending out weekly emails to users
- Incorporated analytics and created scripts to determine power users using Google Analytics and MixPanel

#### **PROFESSIONAL PROJECTS**

# **FORTNITECLIPZ**

Designed a web app that automatically creates highlights of Twitch.tv Fortnite streams by using machine learning/artificial intelligence to recognize when key moments happen during a stream. The backend was built using AWS serverless infrastructure, including IAM, CloudFormation, RDS, S3, API Gateway, Lambda, SQS, MediaConvert, Cloudwatch, and Cognito. Services use FFmpeg and FFprobe to analyze and manipulate video streams. The web client was built using React with Google Analytics. FortniteClipz can be found at http://www.fortniteclipz.com/

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

<b>Programming Bootcamp and Coding School</b>	MakerSquare	-	Austin, TX	2014
<b>Bachelor of Science in Chemical Engineering</b>	Georgia Institute of Technology	-	Atlanta, GA	2009-2013

#### **TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES**

JAVASCRIPT	<ul> <li>AngularJS, Handlebars.js, Ionic, jQuery, Meteor, Node.js, React, Underscore.js, Zepto.js</li> </ul>
AMAZON WEB SERVICES	<ul> <li>API Gateway, CloudFront, CloudWatch, DynamoDB, EC2, ECS, Elastic Transcoder, IAM, Lambda, MediaConvert, RDS, Route 53, S3, Serverless, SQS</li> </ul>
DATABASE	<ul> <li>ActiveRecord, DynamoDB, MesaSQLite, MongoDB, MySQL, NoSQL, PostgreSQL, RDS, RoboMongo, SequelPro, SQLite3</li> </ul>
WEB	<ul><li>Bootstrap, Foundation, Grunt, Gulp.js, Less, Sass, SCSS, Webpack</li></ul>
OTHER	<ul> <li>DApps/Solidity, Docker, FFmpeg/FFprobe, Golang, Java, Kali Linux(Aircrack-ng), Play Framework,</li> </ul>
	Ruby on Rails, Scala, Swift, Xamarin
Analytics	<ul><li>Facebook Pixel, Google Analytics, Mixpanel, Segment</li></ul>
ENGAGEMENT	<ul> <li>Adzerk, Appcues, Branch, Braze, Intercom, Tawk.to</li> </ul>
MANAGEMENT	<ul> <li>Agile, Bitbucket, Confluence, GitHub, JIRA, Rally, Slack, Trello</li> </ul>
NPM	<ul><li>async, cluster, cron, express, moment, mongodb, MySQL, request, rxjs, socket.io, zerorpc, zmq</li></ul>
PIP	ffprobe3, matplotlib, numpy, opency-python, pandas, pillow, pytesseract, requests, seaborn,

streamlink, tensorflow